Guide to the Afrika Bambaataa hip hop archive, circa 1972-2016.
Bambaataa, Afrika hip hop archive,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Afrika Bambaataa hip hop archive, circa 1972-2016.
8094
Afrika Bambaataa, 1957-
600 cubic feet.
Vinyl records and other A/V Recordings, Financial Records, Manuscripts, Memorabilia, Photocopies, Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Approximately 40,000 sound recordings representing Bambaataa's music collection from the 1970s to the present. The archive also includes books, documents, and files relating to the founding and spread of the Universal Zulu Nation; and videos, papers, and clothing.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Afrika Bambaataa is an American disc jockey, singer, and songwriter from the South Bronx, New York. Often called the “Godfather” of Hip Hop, Bambaataa has helped to define Hip Hop since it emerged in the South Bronx in the 1970s. One of a handful of Hip Hop's 1970s originators, Bambaataa gave Hip Hop its name, and was the first to define its core artistic elements - DJing, rapping, break dancing, and graffiti art - under one cultural umbrella. His cultural organization, the Universal Zulu Nation, has helped to spread Hip Hop culture throughout the world. His genre-defining 1982 song "Planet Rock" and subsequent electro-funk tracks have become icons of hip-hop and electronic music. In 2007 he was nominated for induction into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Approximately 40,000 sound recordings representing Bambaataa's music collection from the 1970s to the present. The archive also includes books, documents, and files relating to the founding and spread of the Universal Zulu Nation; and videos, papers, and clothing.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Afrika Bambaataa, 1957-; Universal Zulu Nation (Organization)
Subjects:
African American youth -- Social life and customs.; Disc jockeys.; Electronic music.; Funk (Music).; Hip-hop.; Hip-hop -- Influence.; Hip-hop -- History. -- United States; Music -- Social aspects.; Race relations.; Rap (Music); Rap (Music) -- Political aspects.; Rap musicians.; Hip-hop -- New York.; Rap (Music) -- New York.; Hip-hop; Rap (Music); Rap musicians; Social history
Places:
Bronx (New York, N.Y.) -- Social conditions -- 20th century.; New York (State) -- New York; New York (State) -- Bronx; United States
Form and Genre Terms:
History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to collection restricted until completion of processing, with the exception of vinyl records that have been individually cataloged.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Manuscripts
a. School Papers and Assignments
b. Africa Trip
c. Soul Scrapbooks and Music Writing
d. Notebooks and Miscellaneous Manuscripts
e. Lyrics and Poems
f. Bronx River Neighborhood Center
g. Phone and Contact Lists
Series II. Flyers
Series III. Photographs
Series IV. Personal Papers
a. Personal Papers
b. Press About Bambaataa
c. Catalogs and Mail
Series V. Universal Zulu Nation Documents
a. Infinity Lessons
b. Administration
Series VI. Stage Costumes and Clothing
Series VII. Periodicals and Publications
a. Small Press Publications
b. Periodicals
c. Publications from 3410 De Reimer Ave. Bronx, NY
d. Other Publications
Series VIII. Moving images and audio recordings
a. Video cassettes
a. Audio cassettes
Series IX. Music collection
12 inch vinyl
Sureshots and altered/obscured
Numbered by Bambaataa
Annotated, not numbered (Alphabetical by artist)
A-D
E-H
I-L
L-O
P-S
T-Z
Numbers, unknown and various
Second alpha sequence
Cataloged individually
Not annotated (Alphabetical by artist)
A
B
C
D
E
F
G
H
I
J
K
L
M
N
O
P
Q
R
S
Afrika Bambaataa recordings
Renegades of Rhythm Tour
Test pressings and white labels (not yet cataloged)
Compilations (not yet cataloged)
7 inch vinyl
Numbered (not yet cataloged)
Annotated not numbered (not yet cataloged)
No annotations (not yet cataloged)
Acetates and lacquer discs
Cassettes (not yet cataloged)
CDs (not yet cataloged)
Series X. Ephemera
CONTAINER LIST
- Moving images and audio recordings
  - Video cassettes
    - Unique
      - Compilation of hip hop music videos recorded off of TV, Undated; V-10000; 01:55:58; VHS (Box 95)
        Label read "Jam on the groove-Afrika Bambaataa & Jazzy Jay" but this seems to be a compilation of hip hop music videos recorded off the TV. Year unknown. Digitized as RMM08094_V10000
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, January 27, 1999, 1999-01-27; V-10002; Afrika Bambaataa; 00:29:09; VHS (Box 95)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V10002
        New York, New York
      - Universal Zulu Nation in Japan, 2004-09; V-10003; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:38:44; VHS (Box 95)
        Afrika Bambaataa DJing, hip hop performers, b-boys and b-girls
        Japan
      - Afrika Bambaataa on The McCreary Report, 1988-07-16; V-10015; WNYW; 00:06:54; VHS (Box 95)
        Afrika Bambaataa is interviewed by Bill McCreary on his show The McCreary Report.
        WNYW
      - Afrika Bambaataa & Family perform on Italian television program DOC, 1988; V-10016; 00:12:04; VHS (Box 95)
        Afrika Bambaataa & Family perform 3 songs. Duplicate of V-10014 but this is not PAL and is a better copy.
        DOC
        Italy
      - Zulu Nation on B.E.T., Rap City, Tues. Feb 28, 1995, 1995-02-28; V-10018; B.E.T.; 00:49:25; VHS (Box 95)
        Afrika Bambaataa and the Rock Steady Crew being interviewed, dicussion of the 20th aniversary of Zulu Nation, hip hop music videos by Bambaataa and others. This may be part 2. Digitized as file RMM08094_V10018.
      - Afrika Bambaataa and Family on Italian TV shows, 1988-09; V-10019; 00:31:20; VHS (Box 95)
        Afrika Bambaataa performing, Enzo Avitabile performing, music videos.
      - Afrika Bambaataa on Rap City, 1996, 1996-04-23; V-10022; B.E.T.; 01:37:26; VHS (Box 95)
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, January 26, 1994, 1994-01-26; V-10044; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 95)
      - Afrika Bambaataa, Prince, George Clinton & P.Funk, Undated; V-10057; VHS (Box 95)
      - Universal Zulu Nation May 15, 2002 (vol. 2), 2002-05-15; V-7165; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:50:00; VHS (Box 95)
        Contains lectures by teachers. This is part 2, we do not have part 1. Video digitized as file RMM08094_V07165.
      - Twenty-first Universal Zulu Nation Hip Hop Anniversary, 1995; V-7167; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:33:28; VHS (Box 95)
        Contains DJ scratching contest, MC battles, and performances by KRS-One and DJ Kool. Digitized as file RMM08094_V07167
      - Afrika Bambaataa live DJ jam at Newcastle University in Newcastle, England March 13, 2001, 2001-03-13; V-7175; Afrika Bambaataa; 02:01:34; VHS (Box 95)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V07175.
        Newcastle, England
      - Afrika Bambaataa live DJ set at Reckless Club in Stoke, England, Wednesday March 14, 2001 with b-boys and b-girls dancing., 2001-03-14; V-7176; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:33:26; VHS (Box 95)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V07176.
        Stoke-on-Trent, England
      - Million Youth March in Harlem, New York, 1998-09-08; V-7187; 02:02:50; VHS (Box 95)
        Speeches and footage of the crowd, possibly recorded off of TV or duplicated from produced video. Digitized as file RMM08094_V07187
      - Sixteenth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary (part 2 Saturday); Dance and music performance by Angola Capoeira from Brazil and the Rock Steady Crew; Rock Steady Crew b-boys dancing., 1990-1995; V-7192; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:40:30; VHS (Box 95)
        First part is performances by various well-known MCs and hip-hop groups including Brand Nubian as part of the UZN Hip Hop Anniversary. Second part is a separate event, a dance performance by the Rock Steady Crew and Angola Capoeira. Last part is verious clips of b-boys dancing circa 1995.
      - Afrika Bambaataa, Pharoah and Alien Ness, San Francisco State University, October 24, 2000, 2000-10-24; V-7193; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:04:20; VHS (Box 95)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V07193.
        San Francisco, California
      - Twenty-seventh Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary, November 2001, panels, MC & DJ battles, b-boying, performances., 2001-11-09-2001-11-11; V-9885; Afrika Bambaataa; 06:09:55; VHS (Box 95)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V09885.
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, December 8, 2001: Dr. Phil Valentine., 2001-12-08; V-9887; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:46:19; VHS (Box 95)
        Lecture by Phil Valentine at UZN meeting. Digitized as file RMM08094_V09887 and RMM08094_V09887_audch34.mp4.
      - Universal Zulu Nation presents the Mystical Meeting of the Minds (Day 1), May 14, 2004 (vol. 1), 2004-05-14; V-9889; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:55:47; VHS (Box 95)
        Lectures given by various speakers. Digitized as file RMM08094_V09889.
        Harlem, New York
      - Universal Zulu Nation presents the Mystical Meeting of the Minds (Day 2), May 15, 2004 (vol. 1), 2004-05-15; V-9890; Afrika Bambaataa; 02:02:45; VHS (Box 95)
        Event held at the National Black Theater organized by the Universal Zulu Nation. Includes lectures given by Ashra Kwasi, Hakim Bey, Azzaziel, Booker T. Coleman. Digitized as file RMM08094_V09890 and RMM08094_V09890_audch34.mp4.
      - Universal Zulu Nation presents the Mystical Meeting of the Minds (Day 3), May 16, 2004 (vol. 2), 2004-05-16; V-9891; Afrika Bambaataa; 02:03:12; VHS (Box 95)
        Event held at the National Black Theater, organized by the Universal Zulu Nation. Lectures given by Phil Valentine, Cashus D, and Dr. Nalani. Digitized as file RMM08094_V09891.
      - Twenty-fifth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary (part 1), 1999; V-9893; Afrika Bambaataa; 02:03:40; VHS (Box 95)
        Contains Bambaataa DJing, b-boy competition, DJ battle, interviews.
      - Twenty-fifth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary (part 2), 1999; V-9894; Afrika Bambaataa; 02:03:27; VHS (Box 95)
        Contains DJ battles, b-boying, music performances by hip hop artists.
        After digitization put in order with 7181, 9893, 9894, 9895.
      - Twenty-fifth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary, 1999; V-9895; Afrika Bambaataa; 02:03:42; VHS (Box 95)
        Contains presentation of awards; DJing by Afrika Bambaataa, Jazzy Jay and others; performances by MCs and hip hop groups including the Cold Crush Brothers.
      - Seventeenth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary, 1991; V-9900; Afrika Bambaataa; 00:51:15; VHS (Box 95)
        Raw footage of interviews with attendees by Michael Berman, possibly for a show "On Camera Off Camera." Interviewees include Zulu Nation members Ahmed Henderson and Mr. Biggs, Bro Arthur K, Jalil from the group Whodini, Crazy Legs and others from the Rock Steady Crew, Mercury from the Force MDs, Screamin Rachael, Grand Master Flash, and Flava Flav, plus footage of performances.
        Different content than v-9901, digitize
      - Seventeenth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary, 1991; V-9901; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:52:00; VHS (Box 95)
        Music and dancing, performance by Lovebug Starski, KRS-One, Biz Markie, Jungle Brothers.
      - Twentieth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary, Rock Steady Crew rehearsal., 1994-11-10; V-9903; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:15:25; VHS (Box 95)
        Rock Steady Crew rehearsing and b-boys dancing.
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, November 2, 1994, 1994-11-02; V-9904; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:10:45; VHS (Box 95)
        Meeting includes lectures by various speakers and announcements.
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, January 29, 1997, 1997-01-29; V-9908; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:22:12; VHS (Box 95)
        Lectures by Afrika Bambaataa and T.C. Islam.
      - Leftfield with Afrika Bambaataa at the Lynxx Legends, 1999; V-9912; 00:53:45; VHS (Box 95)
        Produced video about music festival Lynx Phoenix Legends, includes perfomance by Chaka Khan, Grace Jones, Groove Armada, and Leftfield featuring Bambaataa,
        Ibiza
      - Back to Planet Rock: documentation of a 12 hour event, 1998-12-05; V-9915; Burhenne, Nikolaus; 00:59:45; VHS (Box 95)
        Documentary on 12 hour hip hop event including graffiti jam, DJ battle, b-boying and b-girling, performances by hip hop groups and MCs including G.L.O.B.E., Afrika Bambaataa, and Grandmaster Flash
        Eindhoven, Netherlands
      - Footage used for Afrika Bambaataa & Family's "Shout it out" music video, 1988-06-07; V-9927; VHS (Box 95)
      - Here Come the Drums, Japanese hip hop TV special, 1992-04-22; V-9944; Before & After; 01:30:57; VHS (Box 95)
        Documentary about hip hop featuring Afrika Bambaataa and UZN, English language with Japanese subtitles. Production company may be Before & After.
      - Afrika Bambaataa & Family on Italian TV program Azzurro 88 (tape one), 1988; V-9954; 00:17:10; VHS (Box 95)
        Afrika Bambaataa and Family (2 other MC's) perform "Reckless" and he does call and response with the crowd, tape begins with Eddie Grant performing. Seems to be a broadcast of a competition or awards ceremony with other acts also performing. Digitized as file RMM08094_V09954.
      - Afrika Bambaataa & Family on Italian TV program Azzurro 88 (tape two), 1988; V-9955; 00:33:34; VHS (Box 95)
        Afrika Bambaataa and Family (2 other MC's) perform "Reckless" and he does call and response with the crowd. Seems to be a broadcast of a competition or an awards ceremony with other acts also performing. Slightly different broadcast from V-9954. Digitized as file RMM08094_V09955.
      - Zulu Nation on Ricki Lake and Geraldo Rivera; Sly Stone and Muhammed Ali on the Mike Douglas show; Afrika Bambaataa speaking at the Nation of Islam; Dr. Phil Valentine, V-9957; 2:03:06; VHS (Box 95)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V09957.
      - Universal Zulu Nation at the House of Blues, Tommy Boy 20th Anniversary, 2001; V-9958; 01:56:48; VHS (Box 95)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V09958.
      - Afrika Bambaataa and Universal Zulu Nation performing live 1999, 1999; V-9962; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:19:00; VHS (Box 95)
        Afrika Bambaataa DJing, b-boying, and other performers. Screamin Rachael in the audience so this may be in Chicago, IL. Digitized as file RMM08094_V09962.
        Chicago, Illinois
      - Afrika Bambaataa and Family in Yokohama, Japan, 1992-04-18; V-9967; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:06:40; VHS (Box 95)
        Live performance by Afrika Bambaataa and Family, b-boying.
        Yokohama, Japan
      - MTV Rockstoria documentary about hip hop; Yo! MTV Raps Brazil; footage from events, b-boying., 1995; V-9971; Afrika Bambaataa; 02:03:54; VHS (Box 95)
        Compilation of documentary featuring Bambaataa with Portuguese subtitles, plus UZN events in Brazil and b-boying. Year unknown. Digitized as RMM08094_V09971.
        Brazil
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, 1999; V-9973; Afrika Bambaataa; 00:46:05; VHS (Box 95)
        Lectures, announcements, performance. Year unknown. Digitized as RMM08094_V09973.
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, Who are the real Latinos?, 1991; V-9980; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:32:46; VHS (Box 95)
        Year unknown.
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting with presentation on A.I.D.S. Second part of video is a lecture by John Rappoport, MaryAnn Haynes [sp?] other presentations about A.I.D.S. and other issues in the African American community., 1999; V-9984; Afrika Bambaataa; 02:02:59; VHS (Box 95)
      - Dateline segment on hip hop; Afrika Bambaataa and Alien Ness being interviewed Experience Music Project., 2000; V-10023; 02:02:44; VHS (Box 96)
      - Manhattan Lifestyles with Rachael Cain, inverviewing Afrika Bambaataa, Undated; V-10026; VHS (Box 96)
        Dateline segment on the popularity of hip hop. Afrika Bambaataa and Alien Ness speaking with the curator of EMP.
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, August 7, 1996, 1996-08-07; V-10034; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, February 25, 1998, 1998-02-25; V-10035; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, June 3, 1998, 1998-06-03; V-10036; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, February 4, 1998, 1998-02-04; V-10037; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
      - Afrika Bambaataa in Heidelberg, Germany, 2000-07-22; V-10041; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Heidelberg, Germany
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, March 17, 1996, 1996-03-17; V-10042; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
      - Afrika Bambaataa in Europe, 1996; V-10043; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Europe
      - Afrika Bambaataa in Italy and Austria, 2000-06-19; V-10045; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Austria
      - Afrika Bambaataa at the Beyond 2002 Super Festival, 2002-04-13; V-10047; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Afrika Bambaataa performs at the Beyond 2002 Super Festival music festival in Miami, Florida
        Miami, Florida
      - Afrika Bambaataa in Spain, Undated; V-10048; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Spain
      - Afrika Bambaataa in Ireland and United Kingdom, 2001; V-10049; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Ireland
        United Kingdom
      - Afrika Bambaataa in London, United Kingdom, 2001-03; V-10050; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        London, England
      - Afrika Bambaataa in Birmingham, Engand, 2001-03-10; V-10051; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Birmingham, England
      - Back to Planet Rock-Bambaataa in Holland, 1998-12-05; V-10052; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Universal Zulu Nation at the House of Blues; Bambaataa & Maseo in France & England; Tommy Boy 20th Anniversary
        France
        England
      - Universal Zulu Nation in Switzerland, 2000-07; V-10054; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Switzerland
      - Universal Zulu Nation in Utrecht, Holland, 2000-06-24; V-10055; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Utrecht, Netherlands
      - Afrika Bambaataa hosting Rage, 2004-04-24; V-10056; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
      - Trailer for documentary "The b-boy connection"; Trailer for "Life is…" and music video for Goapele's "Closer"; Afrika Bambaataa live in San Francisco, 2001; V-10058; Lopez, Beto 'Mooncricket'; 00:22:16; VHS (Box 96)
        Mooncricket Films
        Afrika Bambaataa
      - Afrika Bambaataa in Koln, Germany, 2000-06-30; V-10059; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Koln, Germany
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, May 31, 2000, 2000-05-31; V-10061; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
      - Black Youth Day, October 27, 1991, 1991-10-27; V-10071; 05:21:26; VHS (Box 96)
      - Universal Zulu Nation meeting, 1993; V-10072; Afrika Bambaataa; LP; VHS (Box 96)
        Universal Zulu Nation meeting: Young Lords, Brother Arthur, BO, T.C. Islam, Brother Prophet (unclear if it's more than one meeting)
      - Afrika Bambaataa in Shinjuku, Tokyo, 2004-09-02; V-10073; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Shinjuku, Japan
      - Afrika Bambaataa in Scotland and Germany, 2001; V-10074; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Scotland
        Germany
      - Zulu Nation live at the Ritz, 1994; V-10076; Afrika Bambaataa; VHS (Box 96)
        Universal Zulu Nation 20th Anniversary. Public Enemy, Tribe Called Quest, Press Conference & More. Note on label "WARNING European PAL System. P.S. Sorry for the quality"
      - Thirtieth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary (tape 1), 2003-11-07-2003-11-09; V-10077; Afrika Bambaataa; done, LP ~01:49:00; VHS (Box 96)
      - Thirtieth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary (tape 2), 2003-11-07-2003-11-09; V-10078; Afrika Bambaataa; done, LP ~02:03:00; VHS (Box 96)
      - Thirtieth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary (tape 3), 2003-11-07-2003-11-09; V-10079; Afrika Bambaataa; done, LP ~01:55:00; VHS (Box 96)
      - Universal Zulu Nation November 14, 2004: Meeting of the Minds (vol. 1), 2004-11-14; V-7162; Afrika Bambaataa; 04:06:29; VHS (Box 96)
        Opens with footage from the Grand Concorse in the Bronx, NY. Contains lectures by teachers and interviews. This is part 1, part 2 continues on V-07163. Video digitized as file RMM08094_V07162
        Bronx, New York
      - Universal Zulu Nation November 14, 2004: Meeting of the Minds (vol. 2), 2004-11-14; V-7163; Afrika Bambaataa; 00:58:00; VHS (Box 96)
        Contains lectures by teachers and interviews. This is part 2, continues after V-07162. Video digitized as file RMM08094_V07163.
      - Universal Zulu Nation May 15, 2004 (vol. 2), 2004-05-15; V-7166; Afrika Bambaataa; 01:50:00; VHS (Box 96)
        Contains lectures by teachers. This is part 2, we do not have part 1. Video digitized as file RMM08094_V07166.
      - Saviors Day 1995 (part 3 and 4) with speech by Minister Farrakhan; Universal Zulu Nation Meeting 1996 with lecture by T.C. Islam "New World Order", 1995-1996; V-7174; 02:19:25; VHS (Box 96)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V07174.
      - Groove wit da gingle bells '96: first Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary in Berlin, Germany, December 25, 1996, 1996-12-25; V-7177; Mansour, Ben; Hertz TV; 01:52:38; VHS (Box 96)
        Produced video titled "Groove wit da gingle bells '96" about hip hop in Berlin, Germany. Footage likely taken from the first Universal Zulu Nation anniversary in Berlin, Germany 1996. Digitized as file RMM08094_V07177
        Berlin, Germany
      - Minister Louis Farrakhan speaking at the Muhammad Mosque No. 7 in New York, New York, April 4, 1993, 1993-04-04; V-7179; 02:35:25; VHS (Box 96)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V07179.
      - 25th Anniversary: Universal Zulu Nation (To:Bam From: Fabel), 1999; V-7181; Afrika Bambaataa; 04:15:55; VHS (Box 96)
        Performances by well-known MCs and rap groups and b-boys dancing. Digitized as file RMM08094_V07181.
      - Lecture Series in Houston, Texas including Afrika Bambaataa, Dr. Leonard Jeffries, Amiri Baraka, and Oba T'Shaka, 1996-04-22-1996-04-25; V-7182; Afrika Bambaataa; 04:08:30; VHS (Box 96)
        Edited title to reflect actual content. Written on label "Lecture Series in Houston, Texas: Afrika Bambaataa; Brother Righteous; Dr. Lenord Jefferies; Mutabaruka". Digitized as file RMM08094_V07182.
        Houston, Texas
      - Universal Zulu Nation Meeting, 1996, 1996; V-7186; Afrika Bambaataa; 02:33:51; VHS (Box 96)
        Guest speakers from various organizations including the Black Panthers collective and the Moorish Temple, lecture by T.C. Islam, and announcements.
      - Twenty-seventh Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary, November 2001, DJ battles and b-boy finals, 2001-11-09-2001-11-11; V-9884; Afrika Bambaataa; 03:41:39; VHS (Box 96)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V09884
      - Twenty-seventh Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary, November 2001, spoken word, lectures, awards, interviews., 2001-11-11; V-9886; Afrika Bambaataa; 04:40:57; VHS (Box 96)
        Digitized as file RMM08094_V09886.
      - Hip Hop concert live in Dallas, TX, 1990; Sixteenth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary, 1990; V-9898; Afrika Bambaataa; 03:05:16; VHS (Box 96)
        First half of tape contains hip hop concert live in Dallas, TX with performances by Special Ed, Slick Rick, Big Daddy Kane, Busy Bee, and L.L. Cool J. 16th Zulu Nation Anniversary: Arthur 4x, Melle Mel, Strickly Connitto, Lord Finesse, DJ Fashion, DJ Jazzy Jay, Ikey C, Ultra Magnetic, Tricky Tee, Queen Mother Rage, Kid Jaz, Just Ice, You and I, Yambu.
        Dallas, Texas
      - Twentieth Universal Zulu Nation Anniversary, 1994-11; V-9906; Afrika Bambaataa; 04:07:00; VHS (Box 96)
        DJ Battle, performances Bounn-E Hunnerz (Bounty Hunters), A Tribe Called Quest, Poison Clan, Chuck D.
      - Compilation of Bambaataa music videos, interviews, documentaries about hip hop and b-boying., 1984; V-9919; Afrika Bambaataa; 02:01:21; VHS (Box 96)
      - Planet rock-Afrika Bambaataa & the Soulsonic Force, 1982; V-9936; Afrika Bambaataa & Soulsonic Force; Afrika Bambaataa; 00:44:30; VHS (Box 96)